<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Christian judges, so called their words judged by the holy men of God, and Christ, and his apostles, and by the heathen ... / by George Fox.</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1676</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 15 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A40132</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1759</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R27993</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">10325344</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 10325344</idno>
            <idno type="VID">44845</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A40132)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 44845)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1384:6)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Christian judges, so called their words judged by the holy men of God, and Christ, and his apostles, and by the heathen ... / by George Fox.</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>11 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1676.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Swearing.</term>
               <term>Society of Friends --  Apologetic works.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:44845:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 96 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:44845:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 96 -->
            <p>THE CHRISTIAN JUDGES, SO CALLED, Their VVords Judged By the Holy Men of God, and Chriſt, and his Apoſtles, and by the <hi>HEATHEN.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Herein you may ſee, that your Words and Carria<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges have been contrary to the People of God of old, and the Prophets, Kings and Judges among the <hi>Jews,</hi> and Chriſt the King of Kings, and his great Apoſtles, and the <hi>Heathens</hi> Governours and Officers.</p>
            <p>And here you may ſee the Carriage and Words of the Holy Mon of God, and of Chriſt, and his A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſtles, and the <hi>Heathens</hi> Rulers.</p>
            <p>By <hi>George Fox.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Printed in the Year, 1676.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:44845:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 97 -->
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:44845:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 97 -->
            <head>THE Chriſtian-Iudge, SO CALLED, Their WORDS Judged by the holy Men of God, and Chriſt, and his Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles, and by the <hi>Heathen.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <hi>ACHAN,</hi> that took the <hi>Babiloniſh</hi> Garments, and Two Hundred Shickles of Silver, and the Wedge of Gold of Fifty Shickles weight; <hi>Joſhua,</hi> the Judge of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> who ſearched the Tribes, and found <hi>Achan</hi> was the Man: now <hi>Joſhua,</hi> the Judge, did not ſay to <hi>Achan, Sirrah,</hi> nor <hi>Thou Raſcal,</hi> nor <hi>Knave,</hi> nor <hi>Rogue,</hi> or <hi>Whoreſon,</hi> as many <hi>Chriſtian-Magiſtrates,</hi> ſo called, will ſay: But <hi>Joſhua</hi> ſaid un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to <hi>Achan, My Son;</hi> mark his Pure Language, and Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voury Expreſſion, and Gracious Words; <hi>My Son, I pray thee, give Glory to the Lord God of</hi> Iſrael, <hi>and make Confeſſion unto him, and tell me what thou haſt done, and hide it not from me.</hi> And then <hi>Achan</hi> confeſſed, <hi>That he had ſinned againſt the Lord God of</hi> Iſrael, <hi>and thus and thus have I done,</hi> above-mentioned. And then <hi>Joſhua</hi> the Judge ſaid, <hi>Why haſt thou troubled</hi> Iſrael?
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:44845:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 98 -->
               <hi>God ſhall trouble thee this day; the Lord</hi> and they ſtoned him with Stones, and burnt his Goods with Fire: And there was no Unſavoury Word given to him, as we read, either <hi>Sirrah,</hi> or <hi>Raſcal,</hi> or <hi>Knave,</hi> or <hi>Whoreſon,</hi> who was worthy of Death, <hi>Joſhua</hi> 7.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Moſes,</hi> the Judge of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> in <hi>Numb.</hi> 15. the Man that gathered Sticks upon the Sabbath-Day, whom they put in Ward until it was revealed of God what they ſhould do to him; and <hi>Moſes</hi> (the Judge) and <hi>Aaron</hi>'s Language was not <hi>Sirrah</hi> or <hi>Raſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal,</hi> but <hi>The Man ſhall be put to Death, ſaith the Lord;</hi> &amp; the Congregation ſtoned him without the Camp. So you may ſee, here was no Unſavoury Language given to him.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Moſes,</hi> in <hi>Exod.</hi> 16. at the Rebelling of <hi>Corah, Dathan</hi> and <hi>Abiram,</hi> when <hi>Moſes</hi> gave Sontence ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Word of the Lord, <hi>If theſe men dye the Common Death of all men, or if they be viſited after the Viſitation of all men, then the Lord hath not ſpoken to me, &amp;c.</hi> And now <hi>Moſes,</hi> the Judge, did not ſay, <hi>Theſe Raſcals,</hi> or <hi>Rogues,</hi> or <hi>Sirrah,</hi> or <hi>Whoreſon,</hi> as many that profeſs themſelves <hi>Chriſtians</hi> will do now.</p>
            <p>And in <hi>Levit.</hi> 24. the Man that they put in Ward till the Mind of the Lord might be ſhewed concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing him, which had Blaſphemed the Name of God, and Curſed; and then the Lord ſaid, <hi>That he ſhould be ſtoned to death;</hi> and the Sentence of <hi>Moſes</hi> was, <hi>That all that heard him, they ſhould lay their Hands on his Head.</hi> And ſo there was no <hi>Sirrah,</hi> nor Unſavou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Speeches given to him, as are uſed among ſome now.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:44845:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 98 -->
And in <hi>Geneſis</hi> 20. when <hi>Abraham</hi> was brought be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore <hi>Abimelech,</hi> the <hi>Heathen,</hi> who was a Ruler, he gave him no Unſavoury Expreſſions, as you may ſee throughout the Chapter.</p>
            <p>And in <hi>Geneſis</hi> 26. When <hi>Iſaac</hi> was brought be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore <hi>Abimelech,</hi> he gave him no Unſavoury Expreſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, nor did not call him <hi>Sirrah</hi> and <hi>Knave</hi> in his Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amination, nor his Father <hi>Abraham</hi> in his Examina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, as many do now that are called <hi>Chriſtians;</hi> and <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bimelech,</hi> do not you look upon him to be as a <hi>Heathen?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And in <hi>Geneſis</hi> 39. when <hi>Joſeph</hi> was caſt into Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon by the <hi>Heathen, Potiphar,</hi> we do not read that he had any Railing Language given to him.</p>
            <p>Neither did the <hi>Heathen, Pharaoh,</hi> when <hi>Moſes</hi> and <hi>Aaron</hi> went before him, give them any Bad Lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guage, as <hi>Sirrah,</hi> and <hi>Knaves,</hi> and the like, as in <hi>Exod.</hi> 5.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Job,</hi> who was a Judge, when <hi>Elihu</hi> ſpoke to him and his Friends, and ſaid, <hi>I know not to give flat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering Titles to Man, let me not reſpect any Man's Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, in ſo doing my Maker will ſoon take me away:</hi> Now <hi>Job</hi> did not ſay, <hi>Sirrah, hold thy Tongue,</hi> nor gave him any Unſavoury Expreſſion, <hi>Job</hi> 32.</p>
            <p>And alſo, ſee the Language of <hi>David</hi> and <hi>Solimon,</hi> and other Officers in <hi>Kings</hi> and <hi>Chronicles,</hi> the Savou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Language they uſed to ſuch as were brought be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore them.</p>
            <p>And alſo <hi>Mordecai</hi> and the <hi>Jews,</hi> who were brought before <hi>Ahaſbuerus,</hi> ſee his ſavoury Language to them, as in <hi>Eſther,</hi> and alſo in the Book of <hi>Nehemiah</hi> 6. and other places.</p>
            <p>And ſuch Officers that were friendly to the <hi>Jews,</hi>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:44845:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 99 -->and ſome were not, yet they did not call them <hi>Sirrahs,</hi> nor <hi>Knaves,</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſons,</hi> and the like.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Iſaiah</hi> and <hi>Jeremiah,</hi> who propheſied to ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral People; and <hi>Jeremiah,</hi> who was caſt into Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon and Dungeon, there was no <hi>Sirrah</hi> or <hi>Knave</hi> gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven to him by the King or Officers, <hi>Jer.</hi> 37.</p>
            <p>And read <hi>Iſaiah</hi> and <hi>Micha,</hi> and the reſt of the Prophets, who propheſied to People, to Rulers and Magiſtrates, and ſee where it can be found that they had any Bad Languages given to them, as <hi>Sirrah,</hi> and the like, either by Rulers of the <hi>Heathen,</hi> or of the <hi>Jews.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And <hi>Nebuchadnezar,</hi> a <hi>Heathen,</hi> in the Examina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Three Children, and his Sentence upon them to the Fiery Furnace, there was no ſuch Lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guage given them as <hi>Sirrah,</hi> and <hi>Knave,</hi> and <hi>Raſcal,</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſon,</hi> in all his Fury and Rage, but called them <hi>Men,</hi> as you may read <hi>Dan.</hi> 3.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Daniel,</hi> when he was brought before <hi>Darius,</hi> in <hi>Dan.</hi> 6. in his Examination and Sentence, had no <hi>Sirrah</hi> or Unſavoury Expreſſions given him, neither by the King nor Officers (when he was ſentenced to the Lyons Den, to be caſt amongſt them) as many give now adayes, who are called <hi>Chriſtians,</hi> and yet ſome of theſe were <hi>Heathens.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And in <hi>Acts</hi> 6, 7. Chap. <hi>Steven,</hi> in his Examina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and Sentence to Death, had not the word <hi>Sirrah</hi> or <hi>Knave</hi> given to him by the Council of the <hi>Jews</hi> in their Sentence to Death.</p>
            <p>And in <hi>Acts</hi> 4. when the Apoſtles, <hi>Peter</hi> and <hi>John,</hi>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:44845:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 99 -->when they were brought before the High Prieſt and Rulers of the <hi>Jews,</hi> and had Sentence given upon them, <hi>Not to preach in the Name of Jeſus,</hi> they called them. <hi>Theſe Men,</hi> and not <hi>Knaves,</hi> nor <hi>Sirreh,</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſon,</hi> as many that call themſelves <hi>Chriſtians</hi> do, below the <hi>Heathen,</hi> and have more fouler Language, and Unciviller, and Ungracious Expreſſions then they.</p>
            <p>And again, <hi>Acts</hi> 22. when <hi>Peter</hi> was put in Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, and <hi>James</hi> put to Death, there were no ſuch words as <hi>Sirrah,</hi> nor <hi>Rogue,</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſon,</hi> by them that priſoned <hi>Peter,</hi> and put <hi>James</hi> to Death.</p>
            <p>And in <hi>Acts</hi> 16. when <hi>Paul</hi> and <hi>Silas</hi> were caſt in Priſon by the Magiſtrates, there were no ſuch words given to them in their Examination and Sentence; they called them <hi>Men,</hi> not <hi>Rogues,</hi> nor <hi>Sirrahs,</hi> nor <hi>Knaves,</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſons:</hi> And when the Magiſtrates had done contrary to the Law, they feared. And ſo ſee how ſhort are many of the <hi>Chriſtian-Rulers</hi> to this Example, who fear not to caſt Innocent People in Priſon, and give them Names beſide, contrary to the <hi>Jews</hi> and <hi>Heathen.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And in <hi>Acts</hi> 19. <hi>Demetrius,</hi> when there was an Uproar about their Gods, he called the Apoſtle, <hi>Paul,</hi> and not <hi>Sirrah,</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſon, Rogue</hi> and <hi>Raſcal:</hi> And this <hi>Demetrius</hi> had much command among the Tradeſmen.</p>
            <p>And when <hi>Paul</hi> was brought before <hi>Ananias</hi> the Prieſt, and the Council of the <hi>Jews,</hi> who profeſſed the Scripture, and lived out of the Life of them; when <hi>Paul</hi> told them, <hi>He had lived in all Good Conſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:44845:5"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 100 -->towards God until that day;</hi> and they could not abide to hear ſpeak of living in a good Conſcience, as the Profeſſors of the Scripture, that live not in the Life, cannot abide to hear ſpeak of living in a good Conſcience now adayes: and <hi>Paul</hi> was not cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led <hi>Knave</hi> and <hi>Sirrah</hi> by <hi>Ananias,</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſon</hi> and <hi>Rogue, Acts</hi> 23. <hi>Acts</hi> 22. Chap. when <hi>Paul</hi> was brought before the chief Captain, in all his Exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation they called him by his Name or <hi>Man,</hi> and not <hi>Sirrah,</hi> and they were <hi>Heathen.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But <hi>Acts</hi> 24. the <hi>Jews,</hi> that denyed Chriſt, and profeſſed Scripture, but out of the Life, which were his Accuſers before the Magiſtrates, they called <hi>Paul</hi> once <hi>A Peſtilent Fellow,</hi> when they accuſed him be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore <hi>Felix</hi> their Governour, as the accuſing Profeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors of Chriſt will do now; who live out of the Life, to us that live in the Life: but <hi>Faelix</hi> gave <hi>Paul</hi> no ſuch Language, as you may read in the Chapter.</p>
            <p>And in <hi>Acts</hi> 25.26. <hi>Feſtus</hi> nor <hi>Agrippa</hi> gave <hi>Paul</hi> no ſuch Language as <hi>Sirrah,</hi> nor <hi>Raſcal,</hi> nor <hi>Knave,</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſon, Rogue,</hi> nor <hi>Jackanapes,</hi> in all his Exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minations and Confeſſions, but heard him patiently, who told him, <hi>He was ſent to turn People from Dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs to Light, and from Satan's Power to God;</hi> and he did not rage againſt <hi>Paul,</hi> and ſay, <hi>It was Deluſions, and a Natural Light, and Jack in the Lanthorn,</hi> as ſome of the Prieſts do now.</p>
            <p>And Chriſt, the Judge of the World, that gave his Sentence upon the Sloathful Servant, that hid his Talent, he called him <hi>Unprofitable Servant, &amp;c.</hi> and not <hi>Sirrah,</hi> though he had ſpoken hard words of
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:44845:5"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 100 -->Chriſt, and called him <hi>Hard Maſter,</hi> yet Chriſt did not call him <hi>Sirrah</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſon,</hi> Mat. 25.</p>
            <p>And in the ſame Chapter, when Chriſt gave his Sentence on them that did not viſit him in Priſon, &amp; Sick, and Naked, did not cloath him, and Hungry, and did not feed him, in their pleading with Chriſt, <hi>When ſaw we thee ſo? Inaſmuch as ye have not done it unto my Brethren,</hi> ſaith Chriſt, <hi>ye did not unto me;</hi> and in Chriſt's Sentence of them into everlaſting Puniſh<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ment, there were no Aggravating Words, as <hi>Sirrah,</hi> and the like.</p>
            <p>And alſo, the Servant that the King had forgiven his Debts, that would not forgive his Fellow-Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant his Debts, but took him by the Throat, and caſt him into Priſon, and ſaid, <hi>Pay me that thou oweſt me;</hi> and then the King caſt this Servant in Priſon a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, whoſe Debts came upon him again, and there was no <hi>Sirrah.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And Chriſt's Sentence upon the Man that had not on his Wedding-Garment, was, <hi>Friend,</hi> and not <hi>Sirrah,</hi> as in <hi>Mat.</hi> 22.</p>
            <p>And alſo <hi>Judas,</hi> that betrayed his Maſter, Chriſt Jeſus, the Lord of Life, and ſold him to the Prieſts, in Chriſt's Sentence upon <hi>Judas,</hi> his words were <hi>Friend,</hi> and not <hi>Sirrah</hi> nor <hi>Whoreſon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And ſo here ye may ſee through along the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, both from Chriſt, and the <hi>Heathen,</hi> and <hi>Jews,</hi> in their Examinations and Sentences, how they gave no ſuch Names as the <hi>Chriſtians</hi> do in their Sentences and Examinations upon People, when they came a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore them, as they do now adayes, who call them,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:44845:6"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 101 -->
               <hi>Sirrah, Rogue, Raſcal, Whoreſon, Jackanapes,</hi> and the like.</p>
            <p>And ſo, <hi>Chriſtians</hi> may ſee through all the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, from <hi>Geneſis</hi> to the <hi>Revelations,</hi> that when any Perſons were brought before any Kings or Rulers, they did not ſay, <hi>Sirrah, Thou Raſcal, Thou Whoreſon, Thou Knave, Thou Rogue, Thou Jackanapes;</hi> we never read ſuch foul-mouth Language in all their Courts, that they did give any ſuch Language when the Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoners came before them.</p>
            <p>And alſo, we never read when any came before the <hi>Jews,</hi> or <hi>Heathen,</hi> or Magiſtrates, in any of their Courts, that they ſaid unto any Perſon, <hi>Sirrah, &amp;c. Put off your Hats, you ill-bred Clowns and Sawcy Fellows.</hi> Now you ſay, <hi>The Scripture is your Rule,</hi> you that profeſs <hi>Chriſtianity,</hi> you may ſee more corrupt words proceed out of your Mouthes, then either out of the <hi>Jews</hi> or <hi>Heathens,</hi> if you will try your Practice and Words by the Scriptures: Do not the Scriptures tell you, <hi>That no Corrupt Communication ſhould proceed out of your Mouthes, and your Words ſhould be Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And Railing <hi>Rabſhakeh</hi> did not give the <hi>Iews</hi> ſuch Language as, <hi>Rogue, Raſcal, Sirrah, Whoreſon</hi> and <hi>Iacke<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>napes.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And Railing Curſing <hi>Shimei</hi> did not call <hi>David</hi> by any ſuch Names as, <hi>Sirrah, Rogue, &amp;c.</hi> when he Cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed and Railed againſt him; neither did <hi>David</hi> give him any ſuch Names, nor <hi>Solomon</hi> when he put him to Death, as you may ſee in the 2d of <hi>Samuel</hi> and the 16th.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:44845:6"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 101 -->
And now I Query, Where and whence the <hi>Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtians</hi> have got all theſe Bad Names, ſeeing neither God, nor Chriſt, nor the Prophets, nor the Judges, nor Kings and Rulers, nor <hi>Heathen,</hi> ever gave any <hi>ſuch</hi> Names, as the Scripture teſtifies of, either a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt the <hi>Iews, Chriſtians</hi> or <hi>Heathen?</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>George Fox.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
